(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-01T04:24:01.240752",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
Release the dreams engraved in your heart!
未来さえ置き去りにして
Leaving even the future behind,
限界など知らない 意味無い！
Knowing no limits, it's meaningless!
この力が光散らす
This power scatters light!
この能力が光散らす
This power scatters light,
その先に遥かな想いを
toward feelings far beyond.
歩いてきた この道を
Walking down this road,
振り返ることしか 出来ないなら…
if all I can do is look back...
出来ないなら…
if I can't do that...
今ここで全てを壊せる
I can destroy everything right here.
暗闇に堕ちる街並み
Streetscapes falling into darkness,
人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
how far can people fight back?
加速するその痛みから
From that accelerating pain,
誰かをきっと守れるよ
I will surely protect someone.
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it right now.
身体中を 光の速さで
Through my entire body at the speed of light,
駆け巡った 確かな予感
a certain premonition raced through.
掴め！望むものなら残さず
Grab it! Leave nothing of what you desire,
輝ける自分らしさで 信じてるよ
shine with your true self, I believe in
あの日の誓いを この瞳に
the vow of that day in these eyes.
光る涙 それさえも強さに なるから
Even shining tears will become my strength.
立ち止まると 少しだけ感じる切なさに
When I stop, the slight sorrow I feel
戸惑う事無いなんて嘘はつけないよ
I can't lie and say I have no hesitations.
宙に舞うコインが描く 放物線が決める運命
The parabola drawn by a coin dancing in the sky decides our fate.
打ち出した答えが今日も 私の胸を駆け巡る
The answer I've fired today still races through my heart.
Sparkling! The shiny lights awaken true desire.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 必ず
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it without fail.
貫いてく 途惑うことなく 傷ついても 走り続ける
Piercing through without hesitation, even if hurt, I keep running.
狙え！凛と煌めく視線は 狂い無く闇を切り裂く
Aim! A coldly glittering gaze cuts through the darkness without straying.
迷いなんて 吹き飛ばせばいい この心が 叫ぶ限り
Just blow away any hesitation, as long as this heart screams,
誰ひとり 邪魔などさせない
I won't let a single person get in my way.
儚く舞う無数の願いは この両手に積もってゆく
Countless fleeting wishes pile up in both my hands.
切り裂く闇に見えてくるのは 重く深く切ない記憶
What comes into view from the torn darkness is heavy, deep, sorrowful memory.
色褪せてく 現実に揺れる 絶望には負けたくない
Fading into reality, swaying, I don't want to lose to despair.
私が今 私であること 胸を張って 全て誇れる！
Being who I am right now, I can proudly boast of everything!
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it right now.
身体中を 光の速さで 駆け巡った 確かな予感
Through my entire body at the speed of light, a certain premonition raced through.
放て！心に刻んだ夢を 未来さえ置き去りにして
Release! The dreams carved in my heart, leaving even the future behind.
限界など知らない 意味無い！
Knowing no limits, it's meaningless!
この能力が光散らす その先に遥かな想いを
This power scatters light, toward feelings far beyond.
突然降る夕立 ああ傘もないや
A sudden evening shower, ah, I don't even have an umbrella.
空のご機嫌なんか知らない
I don't know what mood the sky is in.
季節の変わり目の服は何着りゃいいんだろ
What clothes should I wear for the changing seasons?
春と秋どっかいっちゃったんだよ
Spring and autumn just went somewhere.
息も出来ない 情報の圧力
I can't even breathe, the pressure of information.
めまいの螺旋だ わたしはどこにいる
It's a spiral of dizziness, where am I?
こんなに こんなに 息の音がするのに 変だね 世界の音がしない
With so many sounds of breathing, it's strange, there's no sound of the world.
世界の音が...
The sound of the world...
愛のネタバレ 「別れ」っぽいな
Spoilers for love, seems like "parting"
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぽいな
Spoilers for life, seems like "dying"
なにそれ意味深でかっこいいじゃん…
What's that, it's deep and cool...
それっぽい単語集で踊ってんだ
You're just dancing to words like that
失敬
Excuse me
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる 風
Tu turu tu tu turu "like"
神っぽいな それ 卑俗
That's god-ish, that's vulgar
神っぽいな それ "My God"
That's god-ish, that's "My God"
アイウォンチュー ウォンチュー
I want you, want you
IQが下がっていく感じ
A feeling of IQ decreasing
バカな私は歌うだけ
I'm just a fool singing away
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Shall I spill it all to the stars?
エリクサに張り替える作業も
Even the task of restringing with elixir
なんとなくなんだ
feels somewhat mundane
欠けた爪を少し触る
I touch my chipped nail slightly
半径300mmの身体
A body within a radius of 300mm
で必死に鳴いている
is desperately crying out
音が地獄なら
If the sound is hell,
空気を握って 空を殴るよ
I'll grip the air and punch the sky
何も起きない 私の無気力
Nothing happens to my apathy
だけどさ その手で この鉄を弾いたら
But if I strum this iron with those hands,
何かが変わって見えたような
It felt like something changed
眩しい眩しいそんなに光んないよ
So blinding, don't shine so bright
私のダサイ影がよりいっそう濃くなっちまうだろ
My uncool shadow will only get darker
なんでこんなガツくなっちゃってんだと止まんない
Wondering why I'm getting so desperate, it won't stop
バカな私は歌うだけ
I'm just a fool singing away
うるさいんだって 心臓
My heart is being so noisy
遠い惑星 一人ぼっち いっぱいの音を聞いてきた
On a distant planet, all alone, hearing so many sounds
回り続けていく僕ね 一瞬でもいいから
Spinning endlessly, just for a fraction of a second,
聞いて 聞けよ 私 私 私 はここにいる
Listen, hear me! I, I, I am right here
殴り書きみたいなこと 出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed it out in a state where I couldn't put it into words
なんかになりたいなりたい 何者かに、ぜい！
I want to become something, anybody, hey!
バカな私は歌うだけ
I'm just a fool singing away
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Shall I spill it all to the stars?
聴いてくれて、ありがとう！
Thank you for listening!
聞いてくれるこの環境、とっても嬉しく思います！
I'm so happy to have this environment where you listen!
思いま…ず、ず、ず、ず…
I'm so ha... py... ugh...
いや、ギター弾き語りもね、もうかなり難しくて
Man, guitar and vocal performance is also quite hard,
練習がんばって、どうだったかな？
I worked hard practicing, how was it?
よかった？
Was it good?
嬉しいよー！
I'm so happy!
あ、ホロライブ4期生 角巻わため…
Ah, Hololive 4th Gen Tsunomaki Watame...
今日でなんと！9周年に…じゃなくて9歳になりました！
Today, amazingly, I've turned 9... no, 9 years old!
いや、お祝いは一杯！ありがとうございます！
Yeah, plenty of celebrations! Thank you!
いや、この日のために、もうたくさんたくさん、準備もしてきたので、ぜひ最後まで楽しんでほしいなと思います！
Yeah, I've prepared a lot for this day, so I hope you'll enjoy it till the very end!
じゃかちゃん、よろしくフェイバー！
Jakachan, Yoroshiku Fever!
ってことでね、これ片付けますね。もう使わないのでね。
So, I'm going to tidy this up. Because I won't use it anymore.
はい、ちょっと待っててね。よいしょよいしょ。
Yeah, just wait a second. Heave-ho.
ふー、肩こりんなちまう。
Phew, my shoulders are getting stiff.
いや、待っててくれてありがとうございます！
Man, thank you for waiting!
今日のハッシュタグは、なんと！「#角巻わため生誕祭2025」なので、たくさんポストしていただけると嬉しいです！
Today's hashtag is, amazingly, "#角巻わため生誕祭2025", so I'd be happy if you post a lot!
今日はアニソンナイトフィーバー、楽しんでいけますかー？
Can you enjoy Anison Night Fever today?
わためは、いけますかー！
Can Watame go?!
では、アニソンナイトフィーバー、いくぞー！
Now, Anison Night Fever, let's go!
えっ？なんだこれは？
Huh? What is this?
こんなのステージに置いてあったらいけないでしょ！
You shouldn't leave something like this on stage!
次に
Next,
何これ？
what's this?
えっ？何なの？
Huh? What's going on?
誰これ置いたの？えっ？
Who put this here? Huh?
なんじゃこりゃ！
What on earth is this?!
このま もう少し歩こう 肩を抱き
Let's keep walking like this for a little longer, holding onto each other's shoulders.
消えゆく夢を数え 枯れてく仲間を見た
I counted the fading dreams and saw our friends withering away.
通い慣れた道に迷い込むこのころ
Lately, as I lose my way on this familiar path,
闇がもう一人の自分をつくる
darkness creates another version of myself.
渇いた叫びがくじけそうな胸を突き刺す
A thirsty cry pierces my breaking chest.
君を誘って世界を見たいな
I want to invite you and see the world.
だれにも出せない答えが僕の中にある
The answer that no one can give lies within me.
駆け引きがカギ
Strategy is the key—
とどけ fly at higher game
reach, fly at a higher game!
いくつかの悲しみを一緒に越えただろう？
How many sorrows have we overcome together?
気が済むまで求めたあの日の僕達がいた
We were there, seeking until our hearts were content.
時代が巡るならまたどこかで会えるね
If eras turn, I'm sure we'll meet somewhere again.
その時が来るまで諦めない
Until that time comes, I won't give up.
冷めてく想いはどうしても否けないけど
Though I can't deny these fading feelings,
恋に落ちて変わってくのもいいね
falling in love and changing isn't so bad either.
焦らず騒がずあるがまあと願うから
I'll wish to stay as I am, without rushing or making a fuss,
心に花を 咲かそう just take my heart
and let flowers bloom in our hearts—just take my heart!
渇いた叫びがくじけそうな胸を突き刺す
A thirsty cry pierces my breaking chest.
君を誘って世界を見たいな
I want to invite you and see the world.
だれにも出せない答えが夢の中にある
The answer that no one can give lies within our dreams.
僕を信じて 咲かそう just take my heart
Believe in me, let's seek it—just take my heart!
旅路は続いてく
The journey continues...
カサブタ 作詞・作曲:千綿偉功
[Title: Kasabuta / Lyrics & Music: Chihiro Chiba]
明日へ続く坂道の途中で
On the slope leading to tomorrow,
すれ違う大人たちはつぶやくのさ
the adults I pass by mutter,
「愛とか夢とか理想も解けるけど目の前の現実そんなに甘くない」って
"Love, dreams, and ideals are all well and good, but reality isn't that sweet."
つまづきながらも転がりながらも
Stumbling and rolling along,
カサブタだらけの情熱を忘れたくない
I don't want to forget this passion full of scabs.
大人になれない僕らの強がりをひとつ聞いてくれ
Listen to one piece of bravado from us who cannot become adults.
逃げも隠れもしないから
We won't run or hide,
笑いたい奴だけ笑え
so only those who want to laugh, laugh.
せめて頼ない僕らの自由の芽を摘み取らないで
At least, don't pluck the buds of our unreliable freedom!
水をあげるその役目を果たせばいいんだろう？
You should just fulfill the role of giving us water, right?
何度も繰り返した失敗とか
The mistakes we've repeated many times,
大きく食い違った考えとか
the ideas that have differed greatly—
僕らの基準はとても不確かで昨日より何となく歩幅が広くなった
our standards are very uncertain, but my stride has become somewhat wider than yesterday.
背伸びをしながら打ちのめされながら
While stretching and while being beaten down,
カサブタをちょっとはがすけど答えは出ない
I peel the scab a little, but the answer doesn't come out.
大人になりたい僕らのわがままをひとつ聞いてくれ
Listen to one piece of selfishness from us who want to become adults.
寝ても覚めても縛られる時間を少しだけ止めて
Stop the time that binds us whether we are asleep or awake, just for a little bit.
せめて不甲斐ない僕らの自由の身を切り取らないで
At least, don't cut off the fruits of our unreliable freedom!
赤く熟すその時まで悩めばいいんだろう？
You should just worry until the time it ripens red, right?
大人になれない僕らの強がりをひとつ聞いてくれ
Listen to one piece of bravado from us who cannot become adults.
逃げも隠れもしないから
We won't run or hide,
笑いたい奴だけ笑え
so only those who want to laugh, laugh.
せめて頼ない僕らの自由の芽を摘み取らないで
At least, don't pluck the buds of our unreliable freedom!
水をあげるその役目を果たせばいいんだろう？
You should just fulfill the role of giving us water, right?
Catch You Catch Me 作詞・作曲:広瀬香美
[Title: Catch You Catch Me / Lyrics & Music: Megumi Hirose]
会いたいな 会えないな 切ないな この気持ち
I want to see you, I can't see you, this feeling is painful.
言えないの 言いたいの チャンス逃してばかり
I can't say it, but I want to say it, I only lose my chances.
だって だって 翼広げ二人で
However, however, spreading our wings together,
空をマラソン 夢をユニゾンしたい
I want to marathon through the sky and dream in unison.
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me 待って
Hey, catch you, catch you, catch me, catch me, wait up!
こっちを向いて スキだといって
Look this way and say "I love you."
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
Yeah, nice to meet you, good to see you, certainly!
私の想い あなたのハートに飛んで飛んで飛んでいけ
My feelings will go flying to your heart, flying, flying away!
迷わない
Never getting lost.
たまにね なくなっちゃう 身体のバッテリー
Sometimes, my body's battery runs out,
あなたの笑顔で いつも充電満タン パワー爆発しちゃう
with your smile, I always get fully charged, exploding with power!
会いたいな 会えないな 切ないな
I want to see you, can't see you, it's painful...
この気持ち 言えないな 言いたいな チャンス逃してばかり
This feeling, I want to tell you, but I keep missing my chance...
だって だって 翼広げ二人で
Because, because, spreading our wings together,
空をマラソン 夢をユニゾンしたいな
I want to run a marathon in the sky, harmonize our dreams!
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me 待って
Look, Catch You, Catch You, Catch Me, Catch Me, wait!
こっちをむいて スキだといって
Turn towards me, say you love me!
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
Yes, Nice to Meet You, Good to See You, surely.
私の想い あなたのハートに
My feelings, into your heart,
飛んで 飛んで 飛んでいけ 迷わない
Fly, fly, fly away, without hesitation!
たまにね なくなっちゃう 身体のバッテリー
Sometimes my body's battery runs out and I end up crying,
あなたの笑顔で いつも充電満タン
but with your smile, I'm always fully charged!
パワー爆発しちゃえ
Power explodes!
お願い お願い まずは お友達から
Please, please, let's start as friends first!
笑って 見つめて 楽しい毎日日にしたい
Laugh, gaze at each other, I want to make every day fun!
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me ゼッタイ
Look, Catch You, Catch You, Catch Me, Catch Me, absolutely!
運命だって お似合いだって
It's fate, it suits us!
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
Yes, Nice to Meet You, Good to See You, surely.
誰にも負けない あなたに世界で
I won't lose to anyone, to you in the world!
一番 一番 一番 一番 コイ・シ・テル
The best, the best, the best, the best, I'm in love!
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me 待って
Look, Catch You, Catch You, Catch Me, Catch Me, wait!
こっちをむいて スキだといって
Turn towards me, say you love me!
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
Yes, Nice to Meet You, Good to See You, surely.
私の想い あなたのハートに
My feelings, into your heart,
飛んで 飛んで 飛んでいけ 迷わない
fly, fly, fly away, without hesitation!
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me ゼッタイ
Look, Catch You, Catch You, Catch Me, Catch Me, absolutely!
運命だって お似合いだって
It's fate, it suits us!
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
Yes, Nice to Meet You, Good to See You, surely.
誰にも負けない あなたに世界で
I won't lose to anyone, to you in the world!
一番 一番 一番 一番 コイ・シ・テル
The best, the best, the best, the best, I'm in love!
また夢から覚める、濡れた瞼を開ける
I wake up from a dream again, opening my dampened eyelids.
狂おしいほど思い残す、遠い日の無力さを呪う
I curse the helplessness of a distant day, leaving behind regrets that drive me mad.
身を焼かれるような絶望も糧にはなろうか
Could even despair that burns my body become nourishment?
憧れに焦がれるまま燃やし続けている
I keep burning while yearning for my longings.
キラキラお星様宿したあなたのeyes
Your eyes, which hold glittering stars...
カラカラ渇いて可哀想なlack of 愛?
dry and pitiful, is it lack of love?
全てを孤独から救う眩しい光
Dazzling light that saves everything from loneliness,
僕にだけ落ちる影はあなたのせい?
is the shadow that falls only on me your fault?
致命的な欠落をくれたね
You gave me a fatal lack.
身勝手な巨星、狂わされた生
A selfish giant star, a life driven mad,
お願い、声をきかせて、声をきかせて
please, let me hear your voice, let me hear your voice.
絡まって歪んでしまった傷さえ
Even the wounds that have become entangled and distorted,
くれたのはあなただけ、あなただけ
you were the only one who gave them to me, only you.
お願い、僕を見ていて、僕を見ていて
Please, look at me, look at me.
宿命に刻まれた痛みさえ武器にして
Making even the pain carved into fate a weapon,
いつかの後悔すら照らせるように
so that I can illuminate even the regrets of someday.
あなたがいないと生きていけない 何もかも捧げてしまってもいい
If you're not here, I can't live, it's okay if I offer everything.
あなたの愛がまだ足りない
Your love is still not enough,
欠けたものは何で埋めたらいい?
what should I fill the missing parts with?
致命的、致命的、致命的な愛
Fatal, fatal, fatal love,
運命的、運命的、運命的な"I"
fateful, fateful, fateful "I",
必然的、必然的、必然的な哀
inevitable, inevitable, inevitable sorrow.
僕を見ていてね、最愛のファタール!
Please look at me, my beloved Fatale!
キラキラお星様宿したあなたのeyes
Your eyes, which hold glittering stars...
カラカラ渇いて可哀想なlack of 愛?
dry and pitiful, is it lack of love?
遥か彼方から放たれた美しさに
Fired from far away, by that beauty,
灼かれた眼、もがれた羽根、創造的堕天
burned eyes, plucked wings, creative fall.
あらゆる視界をジャック その輝きはエゴイスティック
Jack all fields of view, that radiance is egoistic.
胸の奥仕舞った感情さえ引っ張り出して昇華して
Pulling out and sublimating even the emotions kept in the depths of my chest,
僕という運命を全部抱きしめていく
I will embrace all the fate called me.
あなたがいないと生きていけない
If you're not here, I can't live,
眩しさでこの身を照らして欲しい
I want you to illuminate this body with your brightness.
あなたの愛がまだ足りない
Your love is still not enough,
夢の中でもらうしかないのに
even though I have no choice but to receive it in a dream.
致命的、致命的、致命的な愛
Fatal, fatal, fatal love,
運命的、運命的、運命的な"I"
fateful, fateful, fateful "I",
必然的、必然的、必然的な哀
inevitable, inevitable, inevitable sorrow.
誰のものでもない、最愛のファタール!
Not anyone's, my beloved Fatale!
何度悔やんだだろう 何度呪っただろう
How many times have I regretted it? How many times have I cursed it?
どれほどの幸福を注いだとしても 満たされることのない器
No matter how much happiness I pour into it, it's a vessel that will never be filled.
何度夢見ただろう 何度願っただろう
How many times have I dreamed of it? How many times have I wished for it?
僕の胸で生み続けている傷を撫でる手を
In my chest, the hand that strokes the wounds I keep birthing...
僕の胸で聴え続けている傷を撫でる手を
The hand stroking the wound echoing in my chest...
この舞台で足掻くことをやめない
I won't stop struggling on this stage.
ただ一つのアイに近づきたい
I want to grow closer to that single love.
固く定まったこの宿命
This destiny that is firmly set.
あの星の光からこぼれた闇
The darkness spilling from the starlight.
あなたがいないと生きていけない
I cannot live without you.
何もかも捧げてしまってもいい
I don't mind sacrificing everything.
あなたの愛がまだ足りない
Your love is still not enough.
欠けたものは何で埋めたらいい?
What should I use to fill the missing void?
致命的、致命的、致命的な愛
Fatal, fatal, fatal love,
運命的、運命的、運命的な“I”
fateful, fateful, fateful "I",
必然的、必然的、必然的な哀
inevitable, inevitable, inevitable sorrow.
僕を見ていてね 最愛のファタール
Please keep watching me, my beloved Fatale!
まるで御伽の話
Like a fairy tale,
終わり迎えた証
proof of reaching the end.
長過ぎる旅路から
From a journey far too long,
切り出した一節
a single passage carved out.
それはかつてこの地に 影を落とした悪を
It was the evil that once cast its shadow on this land,
討ち取りし勇者との 短い旅の記憶
and the memory of a short journey with the hero who defeated it.
物語は終わり 勇者は眠りにつく
The story ends, and the hero falls into slumber,
穏やかな日常を この地に残して
leaving a peaceful everyday life behind in this land.
時の流れは無情に 人を忘れさせる
The flow of time mercilessly makes people forget,
そこに生きた軌跡も 錆び付いていく
and even the traces of life lived there begin to rust.
それでも君の 言葉も願いも勇気も 今も確かに 私の中で
Even so, your words, wishes, and courage are still vividly alive within me today,
生きている
living on.
同じ道を選んだ それだけだった
We chose the same path, that was all.
はずなのに いつの間にかどうして 頬を伝う涙の理由をもっと 知りたいんだ
Yet without realizing it, I want to know more about the reason for the tears streaming down my cheeks.
今更だって 共に歩んだ旅路を辿れば そこに君は居なくとも きっと見つけられる
Even at this late hour, if I trace the journey we walked together, I'm sure I'll find it even if you're not there.
物語は続く 一人の旅へと発つ
The story continues, setting off on a solitary journey.
立ち寄る街で出会う人の 記憶の中に残る君は
You, remaining in the memories of the people I meet in the towns I stop at,
相も変わらずお人好しで 格好つけてばかりだね
are still the same kind-hearted person, always trying to act cool.
あちらこちらに作ったシンボルは 勝ち取った平和の証
The symbols created here and there are proof of the peace achieved.
それすら 未来でいつか 私が一人にならないように あの旅を思い出せるように 残された目印
Even those are markers left so that someday in the future, I won't be alone and I can recall that journey.
まるで御伽の話 終わり迎えた証 私を変えた出会い
Like a fairy tale, proof of reaching the end, an encounter that changed me.
百分の一の旅路
One percent of a journey.
君の勇気をいつか 風がさらって 誰の記憶から消えてしまっても 私が未来に連れていくから
Someday, when the wind carries away your courage and even if it disappears from everyone's memory, I will take it with me into the future.
君の手を取った
I took your hand.
あの日全て始まった くだらなくて思わずふっと笑ってしまうような ありふれた時間が 今も眩しい
That day everything began. The trivial moments that unintentionally make me burst into laughter are still radiant now.
知りたいんだ 今更だって 振り返れば そこにはいつでも 優しく微笑みかける君がいるから
I want to know. Even at this late hour, whenever I look back, you're always there smiling gently at me.
君がいるから
Because you exist.
新たな旅の始まりは 君が守り抜いたこの地に 芽吹いた命と共に
The beginning of a new journey is together with the life that sprouted in the land you protected.
ほんとかん？
Is that so?
ま、令和のアニソンとかを盛り込んでみたんだけど、知ってる曲はありましたか？
Well, I tried incorporating some Reiwa anime songs. Were there any songs you knew?
お気に入りの曲とかあったかな？
Did you find any favorite songs?
なんか好きな曲とかもし見つかったりしたら教えてほしいなと思います。この曲良かったよとか教えてください。
If you found any songs you liked, I'd love for you to tell me. Please let me know, like "This song was great!"
あ、今コメントで教えてくれてもいいんだよ。
Ah, you can tell me in the comments right now, too.
うんうんうんうん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
でも！これで終わりじゃ、ないんだよね。
But! This isn't the end, you know.
1曲だけ！
Just one song!
ま、このあと、ちょっとゲームの曲とかもなんか、アマザテんだけどう、あの、コンセプトが、ある、セットリストになってます。このあと探してもらえると嬉しいです。
Well, after this, we have some game songs too... The setlist has a specific concept. I'd be happy if you look for it afterwards.
ゲストさんもね、まだ出ていない人もいるので、楽しみにしにしててください！はーい！
Also, some guests haven't appeared yet, so please look forward to it! Yay!
よし！
Alright!
では、聞いてください。
Now, please listen.
(演奏中)
(Instrumental Intro)
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
Embracing an unyielding wish,
海の色が赤く染まっていく
The color of the sea dyes crimson,
無重力状態
In a state of weightlessness,
このまま風にさらわれたい
I want to be swept away by the wind like this.
いつも跳べないハードルを
I've always cleared impossible hurdles
負けない気持ちでクリアしてきたけど
with an unyielding spirit, but...
出し切れない実力は誰のせい？
Whose fault is it that I can't give it my all?
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて 色褪せない心の地図
Embracing an unyielding wish, holding my unfading heart's map...
光にかざそう
Up to the light.
どれだけ泣けば朝に出逢えるの
How much must I cry before meeting the morning?
孤独な夜 初めて限界を感じた日
A lonely night, the day I first felt my limits.
きっと恋に落ちるのは 瞬きのようだね 一瞬の情熱だけど
Surely falling in love is like a blink, just a momentary passion, but...
愛に続く坂道で 強さ覚えたい
On the sloping road leading to love, I want to learn strength.
止まらない未来を夢見て
Dreaming of an unstoppable future,
口を閉ざし 瞳を光らせてきたけれど
I closed my mouth and made my eyes shine, but...
もっと大きな 優しさが見えた
I saw an even greater kindness.
(間奏)
(Instrumental Bridge)
跳べないハードルを 負けない気持ちでクリアしてきたけど
I've always cleared impossible hurdles with an unyielding spirit, but...
スタートラインに立つたびに 怯えていた
Every time I stood at the starting line, I was trembling.
止まらない未来を描いて
Sketching an unstoppable future,
腕を伸ばし 心を開いて
Extending my arms and opening my heart,
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
Embracing an unyielding wish,
色褪せない心の地図
Holding my unfading heart's map...
光にかざそう
Up to the light.
(アウトロ)
(Outro)
胸にこみ上げてく
Wellin' up in my chest,
熱く激しい この想い
this burning, intense passion...
僕らは行く 最後の戦場へ
We're heading to the final battlefield,
手を取り合い 誓い合って
holding hands and making a vow.
明日の夜明け前に あの宇宙へと旅立つのさ
Before tomorrow's dawn, we depart into that space!
僕らが地球にいたことだけ
That we were once on Earth—
どうか覚えていて欲しいよ
I hope you'll remember that somehow.
振り返るな 涙を見せるな
Don't look back, don't show your tears!
I GET THE POWER OF LOVE
明日を取り戻すんだ
I'll take back tomorrow!
今こそ 立ち上がれ 運命の戦士よ
Rise up now, warriors of destiny!
稲妻の剣で 敵を蹴散らせ
Scatter the enemy with swords of lightning!
安らぎを夢見る 鋼の勇者よ
Steel heroes dreaming of peace,
守るべき未来と愛を信じて
believe in the future to protect and in love!
永遠へ！ 永遠へ！
To eternity! To eternity!
もしも 力尽きて 闘志の刃砕けても
Even if our strength gives out and fighting spirit shatters,
僕らは二度と戻らない
we will never return,
ともに銀河の海に散ろう
let's scatter together into the galaxy's sea!
恐れるな 誇りを捨てるな
Do not fear, do not cast away your pride!
I GET THE POWER OF LOVE
さぁ 迷わず 行くんだ！
Now, go forth without hesitation!
雄々しく 舞い踊れ 運命の戦士よ
Dance valiantly, warriors of destiny!
金色の翼で 天に羽ばたけ
Spread your golden wings and soar to the heavens!
退くことを知らない 鋼の勇者よ
Steel heroes who know not how to retreat,
燃えたぎるソウルの命ずるままに
following the commands of your burning soul!
永遠へ！ 永遠へ！
To eternity! To eternity!
今こそ 立ち上がれ 運命の戦士よ
Rise up now, warriors of destiny!
稲妻の剣で 敵を蹴散らせ
Scatter the enemy with swords of lightning!
安らぎを夢見る 鋼の勇者よ
Steel heroes dreaming of peace,
守るべき未来と愛を信じて
believe in the future to protect and in love!
永遠へ！ 永遠へ！
To eternity! To eternity!
君は聴こえる？
Can you hear it?
僕のこの声が
My voice
闇に虚しく 吸い込まれた
Swallowed into the vain darkness...
もしも世界が 意味を持つのなら
If the world holds any meaning,
こんな気持ちも 無駄ではない?
Are these feelings not in vain either?
憧れに押しつぶされて あきらめてたんだ
Crushed by my longing, I had given up.
果てない空の色も 知らないで
Not even knowing the endless sky's color,
走り出した
I started running.
想いが今でも この胸を確かに叩いているから
Because those feelings are still firmly beating in my chest.
今日の僕が その先に続く
Today's me continues onward from here,
僕らなりの明日を築いていく
building a tomorrow that is uniquely ours.
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer is right here, as always.
過ぎた季節を 嘆く暇はない
There's no time to lament seasons gone by.
二度と迷って しまわぬように
So I won't lose my way ever again.
数えきれない ほんのささやかな そんな後悔 抱えたまま
Carrying countless, tiny regrets like these,
その背中だけ追いかけて ここまで来たんだ
I chased only your back and came this far.
探していた 僕だけにできること
Searching for the one thing only I can do.
あの日くれた 言葉が今でも この胸に確かに届いているから
Because the words you gave me that day still surely reach my heart.
昨日よりも 今日僕は僕の
Today, even more than yesterday,
生まれてきた理由に気付いていく
I realize the reason why I was born.
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer is right here, as always.
全てがまるでお決まりみたいだった
Everything felt just like clockwork...
尊い日々は まだ終わらない そしてまた...
Precious days are not over yet, and once again...
走り出した
I started running.
想いが今でも この胸を確かに叩いているから
Because those feelings are still firmly beating in my chest.
今日の僕が その先に続く
Today's me continues onward from here,
僕らなりの明日を築いていく
building a tomorrow that is uniquely ours.
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer is right here, as always.
みんなー！
Everyone!
ギンギワラのロボ、かっこよかったー！ロボット乗って飛んじゃったよー！
The Silver Wolf robot was so cool! I got to fly in a robot!
すごい！かっこよかったねー！
Amazing! It was so cool, right?
いやぁ、この3曲はロボットの曲をテーマに歌って踊らせていただきましたー！
Man, these three songs were themed around robot tracks, and I sang and danced to them!
さらにゲストもね、たくさん出演してくれて本当にありがとう！嬉しい！
Also, thank you so much to all the guests who appeared! I'm so happy!
ねぇ、ありがとうございます。
"Hey, thank you so much."
感謝です。
"I'm so grateful."
あ、そういえば
"Oh, come to think of it..."
この頃、この頃みんな気づいたかな?
"Have you all noticed something recently?"
この頃最初から実話そうだったんだけど、あの、小顔ローラー頑張りますって
"Actually, I've been working hard with a facial roller since the start,"
実は私、小顔になったんですよね。こう見えて。
"and my face actually got smaller, believe it or not!"
もうあれだね、顔でかって言われなくなっちゃうな、みんな。めんごめんご。
"People won't be calling me 'big face' anymore. Sorry, sorry!"
そんな変わってないって、嘘じゃない!嘘じゃない!ちゃんとちっちゃくなったもん!
"It hasn't changed? No, it has! It really got smaller!"
あ、この後ね、メンゲン3Dライブも10時15分からまたねチャンネルでやりますので、
"Also, after this, the Mengen 3D Live starts at 10:15 PM on the Matane Channel,"
他の衣装のね、この小顔のわためも見てほしいなと思います。
"so I hope you'll check out Watame with her small face in another outfit too."
歌って踊りますんで是非!10時15分め、め、目ざしに嵌って、お待ちください!
"I'll be singing and dancing, so please wait for it at 10:15!"
でも、まだライブも終わりではありません。
"But the live isn't over yet."
ここで、告知があります!角巻わための新曲
"We have an important announcement! Tsunomaki Watame's new song..."
『ビリ』なんと発表いたします!
"...'Biri' will be announced!"
この後10時からMVが投稿されて、で、楽曲配信が24時から始まります!よろしくお願いします!
"The MV drops at 10 PM, and song distribution starts at midnight! Please check it out!"
神田ジョンさん、篠崎あやとさん、DECO*27さんという夫人で作ったわためのこう新しい部分だったりとか、
"Created with Kanda John, Shinozaki Ayato, and DECO*27, it shows a new side of Watame,"
まっちょ、あんまり歌ったことないような感じの曲になっているかなと思っているので、ぜひ楽しみにしてて下さい。
"and it's a style I haven't sung much before, so I hope you're looking forward to it."
あ、でも、あ、でもこの後、まだ1曲くらい、お、やる気があるか、あ、じゃあ、ビリやろうか。
"Wait, do we have time for one more song after this? Let's do 'Biri'!"
え、あと1曲、ビリ新曲、ぜひみんなに聴いていただきたいなと思うので、最後まで、あのダンスも可愛いんでね、ちょっと一生懸命踊ります。見てください!では、最後の曲、
"So for our last song, please listen to the new track 'Biri.' The dance is super cute too, so I'll dance my hardest! Please watch!"
きいてください。ビリ。
"Please listen. Biri."
昨今 迷子で ぐだぐだぐだ
Lost in modern times, mess, mess, mess
もうハイ or ロー ガチャで ぐちゃぐちゃぐちゃ 更新
High or low, gacha updating in a chaotic mess
合唱 ネガ and ポジる らららら
Chanting, going negative and positive, la la la la
まあ いっかいうたうわ なんてこったいかん
Well, singing once again, what a mess!
ビビビ な ビリビリ
Bzz-bzz-bzz, electric shock
サッコン やる だけ やる しか ない
Nowadays, we've just got to do what we can do
もう ちいさい こと で へこん で らん ない
Can't stay depressed over tiny things anymore
あっとう する まで そだつ だけ だ
Just keep growing until it's overwhelming
さあ しんぱい いら ず の ジェット こーすたー
Now, a worry-free rollercoaster ride
いけ いけちゃん す
Go, go, dance!
とぎ あげた きぼう で おめかし
Dressed up in polished hopes
ざそかし はっぴー で いっぱい
Filled to the brim with apparent happiness
いけ いけちゃん す
Go, go, dance!
たきこん だ ねがい が かおりたつ
The packed wishes waft in the air
いま ぼく に なる ん だ
Now I'm becoming myself
ぼく しか できない こと みとめて ほしい の
I want you to recognize what only I can do
どうせ とか おまって らん ない わ
Can't just think "whatever" anymore
だっせーもーげん ば こん ！ きり きざん で こ
Uncool? Break through with a declaration!
まだ いっとう しょう まで ほうでん が ありそう
There's still discharge ahead until the top prize
とうせん し ちゃう か は ちょうせん しだい オーケー
Whether we win depends on the challenge, okay?
やる が やれない か だ
It's whether we do it or not
はぁめんどい これでエンドい
Ugh, what a pain, is this the end?
たたきつぶした よわねぐちょーびたい
Smashed weak complaints to bits
ゆめ が かなっちゃ って あまく うれ だまれ
Dreams coming true, so sweet, shut up and dance
はかせ は の ー の ー の ー ぐっぱい
Doctor says no, no, no, goodbye
ビビビ な ビリビリ
Bzz-bzz-bzz, electric shock
サッコン やる こと やる だけ ばっく
Nowadays, just doing what needs to be done
もう るいせん あみだ ぜん なき が かくてい
Tear ducts working overtime, crying guaranteed
どうじょう もとめて ほわわわわ
Seeking sympathy, whoa-whoa-whoa
ねえちゃん と だきしめて えっと えっと に
Hold me tight, um, um, smile
にげ にげちゃん す
Run, run, dance!
かおだした ぜつぼう で ごまかし のる かし はっぴー が たんない
Covering up emerging despair, happiness isn't enough in the lyrics
にげ にげちゃん す
Run, run, dance!
あたし を あせない くらべたら くらべる だけ ルーバー
Can't love myself, comparing just makes me a loser
あり なし えらん で ちゃう けど
Choosing between yes or no
よわき に なる かも
Might turn coward
どうせ むり おもって しまっ て しまう わ
Thinking 'it's impossible anyway'
だっせー ゆーげん だ もん ！ かなわ ない もん
Such an uncool declaration! It won't come true
また いっとう しょう ゆび くわえ て みてる の
Staring at the top prize with finger in mouth again
あたし じゃ ない だれ か だっ た の
It wasn't me, it was someone else
のーのー だれ か たおれ て よ
No, no, someone just collapse!
せーの で ちがう の みらい
Ready, set, a different future
いやいや むり だって
No way, impossible!
ぜんしん もっと ハイ に なっ て
Moving forward, getting even higher
おとこらしい ぜいたく で べびー
With bold luxury, baby
息ができない
I can't breathe
ローさん黙ってね？
Row-san, be quiet?
わあわあ全部無駄そうに決まってんじゃん
Wah wah, it's bound to be all useless, right?
はいさん圧が強すぎる ブレーキブレーキ アクセル！
Hai-san, the pressure's too strong, brake brake, accelerator!
かみ合わないね 笑えるくらい
We don't mesh at all, almost laughably so.
それならこのまま行くしかないか
In that case, do we have any choice but to keep going?
やっぱリ分断 それのがいっか
As expected, division is better after all.
大丈夫 無理無理 重なって
It's alright, no way no way, piling up.
僕しか会えないこと 仲良くしてるの
Getting along with the one and only person I can meet,
どうせならからかってみちゃいますか
Shall we tease them since we've come this way?
妄言はバカンス 切り込んでいこう
Delusions are a vacation, let's cut right in.
また一等賞 指加え見てても
Winning first prize again, even if you just watch.
誰かじゃない 僕がいいんだよ OK！
It's not anyone else, I'm the one, okay!
あたしも変えるんだ
I'm going to change too.
アップとっぴー 遊べだっぴー
Up-to-pi, play-dappi.
擦り倒した美学でしゃべりたい
I want to talk with an overused aesthetic.
夢がかなったって止まるな 黙れ
Even if dreams come true, don't stop, shut up.
風刺画はノーノーノーノー… グッバイ
Satires are no no no no... Goodbye.
ビビビなビリビリ
Bibibi, electric shock.
みんな、角巻わため生誕祭2025
Everyone, Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Festival 2025
アニソンNight Fever!!楽しんでいただけましたでしょうか？
Anison Night Fever!! Did you enjoy it?
ここからは告知がありますので、もう少しお付き合いお願いします！
From here on there are announcements, please stick with us!
まず、さっきも告知させていただきましたが、このあと22時にわためチャンネルにて、
First, as announced earlier, at 22:00 tonight on Watame Channel,
角巻わための新曲「ビリ」のMVが公開されます！チャンネルはそのままでお願いします！
Tsunomaki Watame's new song "Biri" MV will premiere! Please tune in!
そして、24時から「ビリ」の楽曲配信も始まりますので、ぜひサードライブを実現させるためにも、買っていただけると嬉しいです！
And starting at 24:00, "Biri" streaming begins, please buy it to support the 3rd live!
さらに、このあと10時から角巻わため誕生日記念2025のグッズが発売開始になります！
Furthermore, starting at 10:00, Birthday Commemoration 2025 goods go on sale!
フルセットはこんな感じなんですが、1つずつ紹介したいと思います！
The full set looks like this, I'd like to introduce them one by one!
まず、ふーみママ描き下ろしのTシャツ！
First, a T-shirt illustrated by Fumi-mama!
正面はポケットから出てるふーみのわためいとがいます。背面には挨拶してるわためがいるので、後ろの人から見ても楽しめるTシャツとなっております！
Front has Fumi's Watamate coming out of a pocket. Back has Watame greeting!
そして、わためいとジャージ！制服衣装とお揃いいろ違いのヒーローのジャージになってまして、背面にはわためが描き下ろしたエアギターがプリントされております！
And Watamate Jersey! Matching hero jersey, with Watame air guitar printed on back!
さらに、ぬいぐるみキーホルダー制服ジャージver.！これがもうめちゃくちゃ可愛い！お出かけにも連れて行きやすいサイズのぬいぐるみです。ぜひいろんなところに連れて行ってください！
Furthermore, plush keychain uniform jersey ver.! This is super cute! Take it everywhere!
そしてラスト！MACCO先生描き下ろしの缶バッジ4種セット！どのわためも可愛いので、ぜひ使ってください！
And last! 4-type tin badge set illustrated by MACCO-sensei!
こちらのフルセットをご購入いただいた方には、ショートボイスセットとチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきます！ボイスは15種類！チェキ風ブロマイドカードには直筆サイン＆メッセージを全員に書かさせていただきます！
Full set includes a short voice set and cheki-style bromide card with handwritten sign!
さらに、タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、去年から発売されたホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚ついてきます！ショップでご購入の方のみ対象、推しをアピールできる推しホロメンカードです！詳細は公式HPにて！
Full set bonus includes an Oshi Holomen card for the Hololive Official Card Game!
とってももりだくさんな最強グッズなので、ぜひたくさん買っていただけると嬉しいです！
It's super packed with the strongest goods, we'd be happy if you'd buy a lot!
そしてこのあと22時15分からはメンゲン3Dライブがありますので、ビリのMVを見て、グッズをチェックして、メンゲンライブもぜひ見に来てください！
After this at 22:15 is membership 3D live, watch MV, check goods, and come see the live!
メンゲンライブでは温度差で風邪を引く可能性が…みんなのこと待ってるねー！
At the membership live there's a chance you might catch a cold... Waiting for everyone!
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for a future that won't stop,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
holding fast to an unyielding wish.
海の色が紅く染まっていく
The color of the ocean is dyeing red,
無重力状態
in a state of weightlessness.
このまま風にさらわれたい
I want to be carried away by the wind like this.
いつも跳べないハードルを
Overcoming hurdles I could never jump before
負けない気持ちでクリアしてきたけど
with a spirit that refuses to lose,
出し切れない実力は 誰のせい?
yet why can't I show my true strength? Whose fault is it?
胸にこみ上げてくる 熱く 激しい この想い
Rising up in my chest is this hot, intense passion.
僕らは行く 最後の戦場へ
We are heading to the final battlefield.
手を取り合い 誓い合って
Taking each other's hands, making promises,
明日の夜明け前に あの宇宙へと旅立つのに
before tomorrow's dawn, we set off into that universe.
僕らが地球にいたことだけ
Just that we were once on Earth—
どうか 覚えていて欲しいよ
please, I want you to remember it.
振り返るな 涙を見せるな
Don't look back, don't show your tears.
I GET THE POWER OF LOVE
明日を取り戻すんだ
we're going to take back tomorrow!
GONG鳴らせ!!
Ring the GONG!
君は聴こえる? 僕のこの声が
Can you hear it? This voice of mine
闇に虚しく 吸い込まれた
being swallowed emptily into the darkness.
もしも世界が 意味を持つなら
If this world holds any meaning,
こんな気持ちも 無駄ではない?
then surely these feelings aren't in vain, right?
憧れに押しつぶされて
Crushed under the weight of my aspirations,
果てしなく空の色も 知らないで
not even knowing the color of the endless sky,
走り出した想いが今でも
the feelings I started running with even now
この胸を確実に叩いているから
are surely pounding against my chest.
どこまでだって 飛べるはずさ
No matter how far, we can surely fly,
光の彼方へ
toward the beyond of light.
描いた夢の場所へ
To the place of the dreams we sketched.
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for a future that won't stop,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
holding fast to an unyielding wish.
胸にこみ上げてくる 熱く 激しい この想い
Rising up in my chest is this hot, intense passion.
僕らは行く 最後の戦場へ
We are heading to the final battlefield.
君は聴こえる? 僕のこの声が
Can you hear it? This voice of mine
闇に虚しく 吸い込まれた
being swallowed emptily into the darkness.
走り出した想いが今でも
The feelings I started running with even now
この胸を確実に叩いているから
are surely pounding against my chest.
どこまでだって 飛べるはずさ
No matter how far, we can surely fly!